So here's my one minute of fame, my acceptance speech, and here's the duck. This is its first time on the U.S. West Coast. I'm going to pass it around. (Laughter) Yeah? You can pass it around. Please note it's a museum specimen, but there's no chance you'll get the avian flu. After winning this prize, my life changed. In the first place, people started to send me all kinds of duck-related things, and I got a real nice collection. (Laughter) More importantly, people started to send me their observations of remarkable animal behavior, and believe me, if there's an animal misbehaving on this planet, I know about it. (Laughter) This is a moose. It's a moose trying to copulate with a bronze statue of a bison. This is in Montana, 2008. This is a frog that tries to copulate with a goldfish. This is the Netherlands, 2011. These are cane toads in Australia. This is roadkill. Please note that this is necrophilia. It's remarkable: the position. The missionary position is very rare in the animal kingdom. These are pigeons in Rotterdam. Barn swallows in Hong Kong, 2004. This is a turkey in Wisconsin on the premises of the Ethan Allen juvenile correctional institution. It took all day, and the prisoners had a great time. So what does this mean? I mean, the question I ask myself, why does this happen in nature? Well, what I concluded from reviewing all these cases is that it is important that this happens only when death is instant and in a dramatic way and in the right position for copulation. At least, I thought it was till I got these slides. And here you see a dead duck. It's been there for three days, and it's laying on its back. So there goes my theory of necrophilia. Another example of the impact of glass buildings on the life of birds. This is Mad Max, a blackbird who lives in Rotterdam. The only thing this bird did was fly against this window from 2004 to 2008, day in and day out. Here he goes, and here's a short video. (Music) (Clunk) (Clunk) So what this bird does is fight his own image. He sees an intruder in his territory, and it's coming all the time and he's there, so there is no end to it. And I thought, in the beginning -- I studied this bird for a couple of years -- that, well, shouldn't the brain of this bird be damaged? It's not. I show you here some slides, some frames from the video, and at the last moment before he hits the glass, he puts his feet in front, and then he bangs against the glass. So I'll conclude to invite you all to Dead Duck Day. That's on June 5 every year. At five minutes to six in the afternoon, we come together at the Natural History Museum in Rotterdam, the duck comes out of the museum, and we try to discuss new ways to prevent birds from colliding with windows. And as you know, or as you may not know, this is one of the major causes of death for birds in the world. In the U.S. alone, a billion birds die in collision with glass buildings. And when it's over, we go to a Chinese restaurant and we have a six-course duck dinner. So I hope to see you next year in Rotterdam, the Netherlands, for Dead Duck Day. Thank you. (Applause) Oh, sorry. May I have my duck back, please? (Laughter) (Applause) Thank you.
Este es mi minuto de gloria, mi discurso de aceptación, y este es el pato. Esta es la primera vez que viene a la costa oeste de Estados Unidos. Lo voy a pasar para que lo vean. (Risas) ¿Bueno? Pueden pasarlo unos a otros. Por favor tengan en cuenta que es un espécimen de museo, no hay ningún riesgo de contraer la gripe aviar. Después de ganar este premio, mi vida cambió. En primer lugar, la gente comenzó a enviarme todo tipo de asuntos relacionados con los patos y obtuve una muy buena colección. (Risas) Más importante aún, la gente comenzó a mandarme sus observaciones de comportamiento animal peculiar, y créanme, si hay un animal que esté comportándose mal en este planeta, yo lo conozco. (Risas) Este es un alce. Es un alce tratando de copular con la estatua de bronce de un bisonte. Se encuentra en Montana y ocurrió en 2008. Aquí tenemos un sapo que trata de copular con un pez dorado. Eso ocurrió en los Países Bajos, el año 2011. Estos son sapos de la caña en Australia. Este es un animal muerto en el camino. Por favor noten que se trata de necrofilia. La posición es notable. La posición del misionero es muy rara en el reino animal. Estas son palomas en Rotterdam. Golondrinas en Hong Kong, en el año 2004. Este es un pavo en Wisconsin en los terrenos del instituto correccional juvenil de Ethan Allen. El acto llevó todo el día, y los prisioneros lo pasaron muy bien. ¿Qué significa esto? Me pregunto: ¿Por qué ocurre esto en la naturaleza? Bueno, llegué a la conclusión estudiando todos estos casos de que es importante que esto suceda solo cuando la muerte haya sido instantánea de manera dramática y en la posición adecuada para permitir la copulación. Por lo menos, eso es lo que creía hasta que obtuve estas diapositivas. Aquí Uds. ven un pato muerto. Ha estado muerto 3 días y está tendido de espaldas. Así que ahí falla mi teoría de la necrofilia. Otro ejemplo del impacto de los edificios de vidrio sobre la vida de las aves. Este es Mad Max, un mirlo que vive en Rotterdam. Lo único que hacía este pájaro era volar contra una ventana de 2004 a 2008, todos los días. Aquí lo vemos, y se lo muestra en este corto video. (Música) (Golpe) (Golpe) Este mirlo pelea contra su propia imagen. En ella ve a un intruso en su propio territorio, y vuelve todo el tiempo y él está ahí, es una lucha sin fin. Estudié esta ave un par de años y pensé: ¿no debería tener daños cerebrales? No los tiene. Les muestro aquí algunas diapositivas, algunos cuadros del video, y en el último momento antes de golpear el vidrio, pone sus patas de frente, y entonces golpea contra el vidrio. Así que terminaré invitándolos al Día del Pato Muerto. Es el 5 de junio de cada año. A las 6 menos 5 de la tarde, nos reunimos en el Museo de Historia Natural de Rotterdam, sacamos al pato del museo, y tratamos de descubrir nuevas maneras de evitar que los pájaros se estrellen contra las ventanas. Y como saben, o quizá no lo saben, esta es una de las principales causas de muerte de pájaros en el mundo. Sólo en Estados Unidos, mueren 1000 millones de aves estrelladas contra los vidrios de los edificios. Y cuando terminamos, nos vamos a un restaurante chino y cenamos pato. Así que espero verlos el próximo año en Rotterdam, Países Bajos, para el Día del Pato Muerto. ¡Gracias! (Aplausos) ¡Oh, perdón! ¿Me pueden devolver el pato por favor? (Risas) (Aplausos) ¡Gracias!